Guide to the Grover C. Sherlin Washington Academy of Sciences (Washington, D.C.) records, 1898-2002 MS2210
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Grover C. Sherlin Washington Academy of Sciences (Washington, D.C.) records
1898-2002
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Sherlin, Grover C.
MS2210
27.5 Linear Feet
In 1882, a federation of the Philosophical, Anthropological, and Biological societies in Washington gathered to form a joint venture titled The Washington Academy of Sciences. The purpose of this formation was to promote joint publications, periodic meetings of these three societies, and to manage courses of popular lectures. The Washington Academy of Sciences formally filed articles of incorporation in 1898. The 21st century objectives of the Washington Academy of Sciences mirror those 19th Century goals and are defined as working to stimulate interest in the sciences and to promote the advancement and the development of the philosophical aspects of science by the Academy membership and through cooperative action by the Affiliated Societies. Membership in the Washington Academy of Sciences is open to all individuals with an interest in science and concerned with the affairs of science and technology. This collection contains meeting minutes, the Journal of the Washington Academy of Sciences, proceedings, financial records, membership records, fellowship publications, committee records, and personal papers belonging to Grover C. Sherlin. Sherlin was past president of the Washington Academy of Sciences. These records date from 1898-2002.
Historical note
In 1882, a federation of the Philosophical, Anthropological, and Biological societies in Washington gathered to form a joint venture titled The Washington Academy of Sciences. The purpose of this formation was to promote joint publications, periodic meetings of these three societies, and to manage courses of popular lectures. The Washington Academy of Sciences formally filed articles of incorporation in 1898. The articles were filed by J.R. Eastman, F.W.Clarke, G.K. Gilbert, Arnold Hague, L.O. Howard, C. Hart Merriam, J.W. Powell, George M. Sternberg, H.N. Stokes, Charles D. Walcott, Lester F. Ward, W. J. McGee, Frank Baker, and Bernard R. Green.
The articles defined the promotion of science as the primary function of the Academy and the specifics discussed the publishing and distributing documents for conducting lectures, conducting, endowing, and assisting investigations in any department of science.
The 21st century objectives of the Washington Academy of Sciences mirror those 19th Century goals and are defined as working to stimulate interest in the sciences and to promote the advancement and the development of the philosophical aspects of science by the Academy membership and through cooperative action by the Affiliated Societies.
Membership in the Washington Academy of Sciences is open to all individuals with an interest in science and concerned with the affairs of science and technology. The Academy is managed by a Board of Managers.
The Academy brings together the entire panoply of local scientific societies and provides individual members the opportunity for face-to-face interaction with a wide variety of scientists and organizational members society-to-society interaction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Allen Barwick, 2001. Dr. Barwick was president of the Washington Academy of Sciences.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains meeting minutes, the Journal of the Washington Academy of Sciences, proceedings, financial records, membership records, fellowship publications, committee records, and personal papers belonging to Grover C. Sherlin. Sherlin was past president of the Washington Academy of Sciences. These records date from 1898-2002.
Arrangement
Organized into eight series: Grover C. Sherlin personal papers, Presidents' records, Board of Managers records, Committee records, Financial records, Joint Board on Science Education records, Membership and fellowship records, and Publications
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Separated Materials
The Journals (1944-1959) found in original boxes 40-43 that were part of Series 8 had water damage and mold. Because these volumes are found at other libraries including at the WRLC consortium the decision was made to remove these boxes from the collection and safely discard.
Science; Washington Academy of Sciences (Washington, D.C.); Joint Commission (Washington, D.C.); Sherlin, Grover C.
- Grover C. Sherlin personal papers, circa 1950-circa 1990; Series 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains notes and correspondence as well as records from the United States National Bureau of Standards.
  - Bills and receipts, circa 1960-circa 1990; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Engineering records and catalogs, circa 1950-circa 1970; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Engineering records and catalogs, circa 1950-circa 1970; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Government briefs and reports, 1958-1964; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - National Bureau of Standards correspondence, 1964; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Personal correspondence and records, circa 1960-circa 1970; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Presidents' records, 1898-2001; Series 2
  Arranged chronologically.
  This series contains records from the President's office of the Washington Academy of Sciences, including correspondence and photographs.
  - Certificates of Incorporation, 1898, 1964, 1984; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - President's messages, 1979-2001; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous directories and programs, 1980-1990; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees correspondence and meeting minutes, 1980-1997; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Office management, 1980-2000; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - John O'Hare correspondence, 1985-1986; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Moses Wharton Young funeral program, 1986; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with other organizations, 1987-1990; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - President's binder, 1988-1989; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - President's binder, 1989-1990; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Albert Gerard Gluckman grant proposal, 1992; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 100th anniversary photos, undated; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Board of Managers records, 1963-2002; Series 3
  This series contains by-laws, meeting minutes, treasurer's reports and budgets, and election records from the Board of Managers of the Washingotn Academy of Sciences.
  - By-laws, 1963; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1966; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Officers and Board of Managers, 1966-1968; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Treasurer's reports/budgets, 1966-1967; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Elections, 1967; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1967; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Elections, 1968; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1968; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Treasurer's reports/proposed budgets, 1968; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Elections, 1969; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - By-laws, 1969; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1969; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1970; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - By-laws, 1970; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1971; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Treasurer's reports/budgets, 1971; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - By-laws, 1972; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Elections, 1972; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1972; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Treasurer's reports/proposed budgets, 1972; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 1973; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Election, 1979; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Meeting agendas/announcements, 1980-2000; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Minutes, 1980; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Treasurer's reports/budgets, 1980-1981; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, 1981; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Secretaries' reports, 1981; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Treasurer's reports/budgets, 1981-1982; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - By-laws, 1982; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Election, 1982; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Minutes, 1982; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Election, 1983; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Minutes, 1983; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - By-laws, 1984; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Elections, 1984; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Minutes, 1984; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - By-laws, 1985; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Elections, 1985; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Minutes, 1985; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - By-laws, 1986; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Elections, 1986; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Treasurer's reports/budgets, 1986-1987; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Elections, 1987; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Treasurer's report/budget, 1987-1988; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - By-laws, 1988; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - By-laws, 1988; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Election, 1988; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Elections/campaign guidelines, 1988; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1988; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Treasurer's reports/budgets, 1988-1989; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - By-laws, 1989; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Elections, 1989; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1989; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Treasurer's reports/budgets, 1989-1990; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - By-laws, 1990; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Election, 1990; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Elections, 1990; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1990; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Treasurer's reports/budgets, 1990-1991; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Election, 1991; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, 1991; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1991-1992; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Elections, 1992; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, 1992; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1992-1993; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Minutes, 1993; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Treasurer's reports/budgets, 1993-1994; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - By-laws, 1994; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Elections, 1994; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Minutes, 1994; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1994-1995; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Election, 1995; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1995; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Treasurer's report/budget, 1995-1996; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Elections, 1996; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1996; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Treasurer's reports/budgets, 1996-1997; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - By-laws, 1997; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Elections, 1997; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1997; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Treasurer's reports/budgets, 1997-1998; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Election, 1998; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1998; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - By-laws, 1999; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Elections, 1999; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1999; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Election, 2000; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 2000; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 2001; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - By-laws, 2002; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Committee records, 1950-2000; Series 4
  Arranged alphabetically by committee, then chronologically.
  This series contains records from a variety of committees that were part of the Washington Academy of Sciences including, Affiliates, Awards, Centennial, Executive, Juiior Academy, and Long Range Planning.
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1981-2000; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Affiliates, 1970; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Affiliates, 1974; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Affiliates, 1980; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Affiliates, 1981; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Affiliates, 1985; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Affiliates, 1986; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Affiliates, 1988-1989; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Affiliates, 1991; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Affiliates, 1993; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Affiliates, 1994; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Affiliates, 1996; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Affiliates, 1997; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Awards, 1967; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Awards, 1968; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Awards, 1969; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Awards, 1970; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Awards, 1971; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Awards, 1972; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Awards, 1973; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Awards, 1977; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Awards, 1981; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Awards, 1982; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Awards, 1983; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Awards, 1984; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Awards, 1985; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Awards, 1986; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Awards, 1987; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Awards, 1988; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Awards, 1990; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Awards, 1991; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Awards, 1992; Series 4 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Awards, 1994; Series 4 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Awards, 1995; Series 4 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Awards, 1995; Series 4 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Awards, 1995; Series 4 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Awards, 1996; Series 4 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Awards, 1997; Series 4 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Awards, 1998; Series 4 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Awards, 1999; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Awards, 2000; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Awards, 2001; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Centennial Committee, 1997-1998; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Executive Committee, 1972-1990; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Junior Academy, 1955; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Junior Academy, 1961; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Junior Academy, 1970-1971; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Junior Academy, 1973; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Junior Academy, 1975; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Junior Academy, 1980-1981; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Junior Academy, 1982-1983; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Junior Academy, 1984-1985; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Junior Academy, 1986-1987; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Junior Academy, 1990; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Junior Academy, 1991; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Junior Academy, 1994; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Junior Academy, 1997; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Junior Academy, 1998; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Junior Academy, 1999; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Junior Academy, 2000; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Junior Academy Award Certificates, undated; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, 1980; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1965; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1966-1967; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1967-1968; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1969-1970; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1970-1971; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1971-1972; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1972-1973; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1973-1974; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1974-1975; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1975-1982; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1979-1980; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1980-1982; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1982-1983; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Meetings, 1983-1985; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Meetings, 1983-1984; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1984-1985; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1985-1986; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1986-1987; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1987-1988; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1988-1989; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1989-1990; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1990-1991; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1991-1992; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1992-1993; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1993-1994; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Meetings, 1995-1996; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Meetings, 1996-1997; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Meetings & Conferences, 1997-1998; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Membership Committee, 1982-2000; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Policy Planning Committee, 1969-1980; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Program Planning Committee, 1974-1985; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Russian Academy, 1993; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - School Contact Committee minutes, circa 1950-circa 1960; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Recommendations of School Contacts Committee to Science Fair Association, circa 1950; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Website, 1994-1998; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Financial records, 1962-1999; Series 5
  This series contains financial records, tax documents, and bank records of the Washington Academy of Sciences.
  - Junior Academy check binder, 1962-1968; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Subscriptions, 1963-1969; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Financial records, 1968; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Financial records, 1970; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Financial records, 1972; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Financial records, 1975; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Financial records, 1980-1981; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous financial records, 1980-1985; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous financial records, 1980-1985; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Financial records, 1981-1982; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Financial records, 1982-1983; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Ledger book 1 and 2, 1983-1984; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Financial records, 1984; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Example IRS filings, 1984-1988; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Ledger books, 1984-1988; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Dues records, 1985; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Finanical records, 1985; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Royalty statement, 1985; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Tax form 990, 1985; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - United Virginia Bank records, 1985; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Ledger book 4 and 5, 1985-1986; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Financial records, 1986; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Financial records, 1987-1988; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Financial records, 1989; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Crestar account summaries, 1989-1990; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Crestar account summaries, 1989-1990; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Financial records, 1990; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Perpetual account summaries, 1990; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Financial records, 1991; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Financial records, 1992; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Financial records, 1993; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Financial records, 1994; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Financial records, 1995; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Financial records, 1996; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Financial records, 1998; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Financial records, 1999; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Joint Board on Science Education records, 1950-2000; Series 6
  This series contains general records, Science Fair records, and directories of the Joint Board on Science Education.
  Organized into 3 subseries: Records, Science fairs, Directories.
  - Records, 1959-1997; Series 6 Subseries 1
    This subseries includes meeting minutes, grant proposals, correspondence, and other records of the Joint Board on Science Education.
    - Application for National Science Foundation Grant, 1968; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Attendance, 1978-1980; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Biology, 1969; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Chemistry, 1968; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Comments of participants of Joint Board conferences, 1969; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Comments of non-participants on JBSE conferences, 1969; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Contact members, Catholic University of America, 1971; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Contact recognition, 1971-1972; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Contributing member cards, 1956-1957; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1956; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1971; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1972; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1979; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence to National Science Foundation, 1969-1970; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Department of Commerce "Brief History of Measurement Systems", 1976; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - E/E Act proposal, 1970-1974; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Engineering, 1969; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Funds appeal, 1971; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Funds appeal, 1972; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - General Science, 1968; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Grant reimbursements records, 1966-1968; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - High school subs, undated; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - History of Joint Board on Science Education, undated; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Inner City committee, 1971-1972; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Masters, 1971; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Mathematics, 1968; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Meeting agenda, 1972; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Meeting minutes, 1959-1960; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Meeting minutes 1 of 2, 1960-1961; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Meeting minutes 2 of 2, 1960-1961; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Meeting minutes, 1960-1965; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Meeting minutes, 1965-1966; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Meeting minutes, 1966-1967; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Meeting minutes, 1967-1968; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Meeting minutes, 1968-1969; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Meeting minutes, 1971-1972; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Meeting minutes, 1972-1979; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Meeting minutes, 1974-1975; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Meeting minutes, 1975-1977; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Meeting minutes, 1989; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Meeting minutes, by-laws, reports, 1972-1990; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Meetings and miscellaneous, 1956-1958; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Membership, 1972; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Member questionnaire, 1970; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Memoranda, 1973-1974; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Memos and notes, 1965-1966; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Metropolitan Washington Science Bureau, 1961-1962; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous pamphlets and records, circa 1968; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous records, 1980-1985; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - NASA Space Transportation System, 1977; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 15, Folder 9)